[
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  How many significant figures are in the number 0.00750?",
        "Answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  Subtract the following 2 numbers and give your answer with the proper significant figures:  25.101 \u0152 0.9608",
        "Answer": "24.140"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following is closest to the meaning of the suffix \u201alith\u2122:  W)  outside X)  stone Y)  side Z)  surface",
        "Answer": "X)  STONE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer   Rounded to the nearest whole number, how many feet does light travel in one-billionth of one second?",
        "Answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "ENCE  Multiple Choice  Most VOC\u2122s, or volatile organic compounds, are:  W)  hydrocarbons X)  oxides Y)  nitrogenous wastes Z)  particulates",
        "Answer": "W)  HYDROCARBONS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer A 25-microliter blood serum sample contains 50 micrograms of an enzyme.  What is the enzyme concentration in parts per million?",
        "Answer": "2,000"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following has the largest seasonal hypoxic zone in coastal waters of the western hemisphere:  W)  the Chesapeake Bay X)  the Gulf of Maine Y)  the Gulf of Mexico Z)  Hudson Bay",
        "Answer": "Y)  THE GULF OF MEXICO"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  The hypoxic zone in the Gulf of Mexico, and many other areas in the world, is largely caused by the influx of which of the following into waterways:   W)  phosphorous X)  nitrogen  Y)  potassium Z)  sulfur",
        "Answer": "X)  NITROGEN"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "ENCE  Multiple Choice  Ed the entomologist is setting up mosquito traps in a farmer\u2122s field in Nebraska.  Which of the following would be the BEST mosquito attractant to ensure he traps the greatest number and variety of mosquitoes:  W)  oxygen  X)  nitrogen  Y)  dry ice Z)  methane",
        "Answer": "Y)  DRY ICE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  Rounded to the nearest whole number, convert 3,000 meters per second into kilometers per hour:",
        "Answer": "10,800"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  A standard rain gauge consists of a metal canister open at the top in which a funnel drains rainwater into a narrow cylinder.  Each time they are deployed to the field, a small amount of light oil is added to the cylinder.  This is done to:  W)  deter birds from drinking the water X)  stop the canister from oxidizing Y)  prevent the growth of blue-green algae Z)  prevent water evaporation",
        "Answer": "Z)  PREVENT WATER EVAPORATION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following is a widely-used analgesic and antipyretic medication which is not considered an NSAID (read as: en-say\u2122d):  W)  acetylcysteine X)  acetaminophen Y)  acetylsalicylic acid Z)  ibuprophen",
        "Answer": "X)  ACETAMINOPHEN"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "ENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following is NOT true of coelacanths (read as: SEE-laa-kanths):  W)  the coelacanth is considered a living fossil X)  the coelacanth is a bottom dweller fish and uses its 4 limbs for walking Y)  the coelacanth is essentially inedible to humans Z)  the coelacanth gives birth to live young",
        "Answer": "X)  THE COELACANTH IS A"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  What alkene is a plant pigment that is a precursor to vitamin-A?",
        "Answer": "BETA-CAROTENE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following is the p value for F = 0 in an ANOVA F test:  W)  0.00 X)  0.50 Y)  0.95 Z)  1.00",
        "Answer": "Z)  1.00"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  Name all of the following 4 choices that are characteristic of scientific publications:  1) scientific papers are peer reviewed  2) scientific papers present more detailed data  3) conclusions in scientific papers are supported by original data in the publication  4) scientific papers have data that has been proven to be true",
        "Answer": "1;  2;  3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  Pitchblende is one of the main ores of what element?",
        "Answer": "URANIUM"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  Order the following 3 temperature values from the COOLEST to the WARMEST:  32\u00baC;  85\u00baF;  310 K",
        "Answer": "85\u00baF;  32\u00baC;  310 K"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  The largest deposits of diatomite, or diatomaceous earth, are typically found in which of the following regions of the U.S.:  W)  western X)  eastern Y)  midwest Z)  southern",
        "Answer": "W)  WESTERN"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Diatomite, or diatomaceous earth, is readily available in the U.S. and is used primarily for which of the following functions:  W)  soil improvement X)  crushed stone Y)  filtering agent  Z)  lubricant",
        "Answer": "Y)  FILTERING AGENT"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  Order the following 3 hexadecimal numbers from SMALLEST to LARGEST:  3E8;  BB8;  1F4;",
        "Answer": "1F4;  3E8;  BB8"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "ENCE  Multiple Choice  An experiment aboard a recent Space Shuttle mission exposed Salmonella typhimurium (read as: TIE-fee-muhr-EE-um) to a space environment.  Which of the following resulted when the bacteria came back to Earth:  W)  they were more virulent X)  they were less virulent Y)  they had about the same virulence Z)  they changed into a new but similar species of bacteria",
        "Answer": "W)  THEY WERE MORE VIRULENT"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Because of its linear-temperature relationship and its chemical inertness, which of the following materials is almost always used in resistance temperature detectors:  W)  mercury X)  platinum Y)  iron Z)  brass",
        "Answer": "X)  PLATINUM"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following is the main advantage for the use of geothermal heat pumps in the U.S.:  W)  geothermal steam reservoirs can be tapped almost anywhere in the U.S. X)  heat can be delivered directly for its intended use Y)  steam can be used to directly generate electricity Z)  all areas of the U.S. have nearly constant shallow-ground temperatures",
        "Answer": "Z)  ALL AREAS OF THE U.S. HAVE NEARLY CONSTANT SHALLOW-GROUND TEMPERATURES"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "ENCE  Multiple Choice  In which of the following processes would isinglass (read as: eye-zen-glass) most likely be used:  W)  clarification of beers and wines X)  baking of yeast-free breads Y)  glazing of ceramics Z)  thickening of puddings",
        "Answer": "W)  CLARIFICATION OF BEERS AND WINES"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "ENCE  Multiple Choice  In which of the following instances would using a student t-test be most appropriate:  W)  comparing yes or no answers on a single question on a questionnaire  X)  determining statistical differences between 5 different age groups of males that received a drug that increases red blood cell production Y)  finding the statistical differences between two groups in an experiment on a drug\u2122s effect in raising or lowering blood pressure Z)  comparing the strengths of 5 different types of fishing lines",
        "Answer": "Y)  FINDING THE STATISTICAL DIFFERENCES BETWEEN TWO GROUPS IN AN EXPERIMENT ON A DRUG\u2122S EFFECT IN RAISING OR LOWERING BLOOD PRESSURE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Clean or unpolluted rain water has a pH of about:  W)  5.6 X)  6.5 Y)  7.0 Z)  7.6",
        "Answer": "W)  5.6"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following plays the greatest role in the effect of acid rain on the environment:  W)  the ability of soils and bedrock to neutralize the acid X)  the initial pH of the rain in the upper troposphere Y)  low-level ozone concentration Z)  temperature of the troposphere",
        "Answer": "W)  THE ABILITY OF SOILS AND BEDROCK"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "ENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following is the source of alpha radiation most often used in household ionization smoke detectors:  W)  americium-241 X)  uranium-238 Y)  radium-226 Z)  iron-59",
        "Answer": "W)  AMERICIUM-241"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  Calculate the heating degree day in the U.S. if the day\u2122s high temperature is 70\u00baF and the low is 30\u00baF:",
        "Answer": "15"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  According to EPA nationwide emission trends for common air pollutants and excluding fires and dust, which of the following  accounted for the least amount of emissions in the past 5 years:  W)  volatile organic compounds X)  carbon monoxide Y)  sulfur dioxide Z)  particulate matter",
        "Answer": "Z)  PARTICULATE MATTER"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer   Without leap days every 4 years, the winter solstice would start on what month and day after 70 years?",
        "Answer": "JANUARY 7"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  What are the Ice Cube observatory under construction at the South Pole and the ANTARES telescope off the coast of France primarily designed to detect?",
        "Answer": "NEUTRINOS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  During the winter solstice in the northern hemisphere, which of the following northern latitude positions will have a day length of 10.1 hours:  W)  30\u00ba X)  40\u00ba Y)  50\u00ba Z)  60\u00ba",
        "Answer": "W)  30\u00ba"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "ENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following best illustrates a limitation of a supercapacitor, or electric double-layer capacitor, versus an electrochemical battery:  W)  virtually unlimited cycle life X)  rapid recharging Y)  low impedance Z)  high self-discharge rate",
        "Answer": "Z)  HIGH SELF-DISCHARGE RATE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  If it is 7:47 AM, Tuesday September 23rd  in  Beijing China at 116\u00ba east longitude, what day and time, respectively, would it be in London, England?",
        "Answer": "TUESDAY;  12:47 AM"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following age groups would have the most brown fat per kilogram of body weight:  W)  infant X)  adolescent Y)  middle age Z)  elderly",
        "Answer": "W)  INFANT"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following physiological processes generates most of the heat needed to keep an infant warm:  W)  digestion of food in the gut X)  oxidative metabolism Y)  inspiration of air Z)  bacterial activity in the gut",
        "Answer": "X)  OXIDATIVE METABOLISM"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "ENCE  Multiple Choice  The related quantities charted on a line graph are most often called:  W)  results  X)  lines Y)  sets Z)  variables",
        "Answer": "Z)  VARIABLES"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  How many grams of sodium chloride is in 2,000 milliliters of 0.9% NaCl solution?",
        "Answer": "18"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  The fertilizer potash provides plants with what element necessary for healthy growth and which is also the seventh most abundant element on Earth?",
        "Answer": "POTASSIUM"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  From what protein is gelatin, which is used as a food additive, most commonly derived?",
        "Answer": "COLLAGEN"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  A hexadecimal number is a numeral system with a radix or a base of what?",
        "Answer": "16"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  Convert a pressure of 1.2 atmospheres into millimeters mercury:",
        "Answer": "912"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer   The lush forest of the Pacific northwest is classified as what type of rain forest?",
        "Answer": "TEMPERATE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  The reaction of lead oxide in the presence of what acid is fundamental to the operation of the lead-acid rechargeable battery found in most cars?",
        "Answer": "SULFURIC ACID"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  1 bar equals how many Pascals?",
        "Answer": "100,000"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  Meteorologists commonly use the hectopascal for air pressure.  1,000 hectopascals equals how many millibars?",
        "Answer": "1,000"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Bioluminescence is a phenomenon most common in which of the following environments:  W)  marine X)  fresh water Y)  land Z)  atmosphere",
        "Answer": "W)  MARINE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following is a mixing incompatibility of common household products that can produce toxic products:  W)  vinegar and baking soda X)  vinegar and bleach  Y)  vinegar and borax  Z)  castile soap and salt",
        "Answer": "X)  VINEGAR AND BLEACH"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "ENCE  Multiple Choice  What is the MOST accurate term for predicting values of data that are located between known data points on a line graph:  W)  extrapolation X)  extension Y)  interpolation Z)  cheating",
        "Answer": "Y)  INTERPOLATION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  Convert 0.001 grams per cubic millimeter into kilograms per cubic meter:",
        "Answer": "1,000"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Biomagnification is MOST likely to result in the concentration of toxic chemicals in:  W)  chemoautotrophs  X)  eutrophic lakes Y)  primary consumers Z)  primary producers",
        "Answer": "Y)  PRIMARY CONSUMERS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  HDPE is a tough plastic often used for the manufacture of toys.  What monomer is the primary repeating unit in this polymer?",
        "Answer": "ETHYLENE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  Giving your answer to the first decimal place, an increase  of 1\u00baC is equivalent to an increase of how many degrees Fahrenheit?",
        "Answer": "1.8"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  Convert 140\u00baF into degrees Celsius:",
        "Answer": "60"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following is NOT true:  W)  only a few harmful algal bloom species actually produce toxins that are poisonous to people X)  algal blooms occur in marine and freshwater environments Y)  algal blooms can occur in the open ocean far from any coastal inlets Z)  pollution is always to blame for harmful algal blooms along coastal waters",
        "Answer": "Z)  POLLUTION IS ALWAYS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  500 metric gigatons is approximately equal to how many pounds:  W)  1.1 trillion X)  11 trillion Y)  110 trillion Z)  1,100 trillion",
        "Answer": "Z)  1,100 TRILLION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Pyrex glass contains many of the same components as soda lime glass but in addition contains at least 5%:  W)  boric acid X)  pure silica Y)  clay Z)  dyes",
        "Answer": "W)"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following BEST describes the function of boric acid in the manufacture of Pyrex or borosilicate glass:  W)  makes the glass more scratch-resistant  X)  makes the glass more brittle Y)  reduces the linear coefficient of expansion of the glass Z)  reduces the effect of detrimental ultraviolet light exposure",
        "Answer": "Y)  REDUCES THE LINEAR COEFFICIENT OF EXPANSION OF THE GLASS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "ENCE  Multiple Choice  The Chesapeake Bay Foundation has enlisted the help of volunteers to raise oysters within cages tied to docks just below the water\u2122s surface.  Which of the following is the BEST reason why these amateur conservationists will not be tempted to eat their oysters:  W)  they are genetically engineered and their impact on human heath has not been assessed  X)  they were irradiated prior to seeding to ensure they were disease-free Y)  there is a water pollution advisory against eating oysters grown within most of the watershed Z)  some are equipped with a radio transmitter to allow biologists to easily measure population changes",
        "Answer": "Y)  THERE IS A WATER POLLUTION ADVISORY AGAINST EATING OYSTERS GROWN WITHIN MOST OF THE WATERSHED"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  If one of Earth\u2122s tectonic plates moves at a rate of about 10 centimeters per year, how many kilometers will it move in 100 million years?",
        "Answer": "10,000"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Geothermal power plants use which of the following to generate electricity:  W)  coal X)  steam Y)  sunlight  Z)  pressurized water",
        "Answer": "X)  STEAM"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Diatoms are:  W)  bacteria X)  twinned crystals Y)  seaweed Z)  algae",
        "Answer": "Z)  ALGAE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "ENCE  Multiple Choice  The sea nettle is the Bering Sea\u2122s most common:  W)  jellyfish X)  crab Y)  sea urchin Z)  walleye pollock",
        "Answer": "W)  JELLYFISH"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "ENCE  Multiple Choice  1 cubic foot per second equals approximately how many gallons per minutes:  W)  256 X)  449 Y)  646 Z)  724",
        "Answer": "X)  449"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  In the northern hemisphere, which of the following degrees latitude would experience a length of day of 6 months:  W)  0 X)  30 Y)  60 Z)  90",
        "Answer": "Z)  90"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following is a substance that is generally considered friable:  W)  concrete X)  topaz Y)  quartz Z)  perlite",
        "Answer": "Z)  PERLITE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  Name 2 of the following 4 choices that are the 2 main logical reasoning methods used in science:  inductive;  synthetic;  observational;  deductive",
        "Answer": "INDUCTIVE;  DEDUCTIVE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  To the nearest whole number, convert 50\u00baF into kelvin:",
        "Answer": "283"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following is a jaw-less fish:  W)  lungfish X)  catfish Y)  lamprey Z)  sturgeon",
        "Answer": "Y)  LAMPREY"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  In the northern hemisphere, name all of the following 4 northern degree latitudes that will experience a 12-hour length of day during the vernal equinox:   0\u00ba;  10\u00ba;  15\u00ba;  20\u00ba",
        "Answer": "ALL"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "ENCE  Multiple Choice  One kilogram is nearly equivalent to how many pounds:  W)  454 X)  4.54 Y)  220 Z)  2.2",
        "Answer": "Z)  2.2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "ENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following reagents would be labeled as highly flammable because of its low flash point:  W)  glycerol  X)  methanol Y)  carbon tetrachloride Z)  sulfuric acid",
        "Answer": "X)  METHANOL"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "Answer  In the mks system, what are the 3 fundamental units?",
        "Answer": "METERS;  KILOGRAMS;  SECONDS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  Giving your answer in scientific notation, convert 10 square meters into square millimeters:",
        "Answer": "1 ! 107"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "ENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following is an intestinal worm which grows to about 25 centimeters in length and is transferred from person to person by way of contaminated soil:  W)  Ascaris  (read as: as-KAH-ris) X)  guinea worm Y)  shistosomiasis  (read as: SHISS-toe-so-MY-ah-sis) Z)  lymphatic filariasis (read as: fil-AH-ree-AH-sis)",
        "Answer": "W)  ASCARIS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "ENCE  Multiple Choice  Shock is often a life-threatening health condition that is typically and most directly caused by:  W)  low blood pH X)  loss of brain function Y)  extremely high cardiac output  Z)  low blood pressure",
        "Answer": "Z)  LOW BLOOD PRESSURE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following statements is LEAST accurate:  W)  tetraethyl lead was once commonly added to gasoline to prevent engine knocking X)  free radicals are not known to play a role in biological processes Y)  catalase reacts with hydrogen peroxide to form water and oxygen Z)  bottled mineral water typically contains higher total dissolved solids than tap water",
        "Answer": "X)  FREE RADICALS ARE NOT KNOWN"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Recent evidence suggests that comets arise not only from reservoirs of the Kuiper Belt and Oort Cloud but also from:  W)  the main asteroid belt X)  a belt between Neptune and Pluto Y)  a belt about 100 astronomical units beyond Pluto Z)  at the heliopause",
        "Answer": "W)  THE MAIN ASTEROID BELT"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "ENCE  Multiple Choice  Rooted plants that grow below the surface of the water are called submerged plants.  Which of the following is BEST classified as a freshwater submerged plant:  W)  common reed X)  sedges Y)  water lilies Z)  water milfoil",
        "Answer": "Z)  WATER MILFOIL"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  What is the decimal number 84 in binary?",
        "Answer": "1010100"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following is NOT true:  W)  nanometer-thick films that roll themselves into tubes and other useful shapes have been recently discovered X)  counting annual growth lines in dinosaur bones can be used to estimate their age at death Y)  amphibian population declines and extinctions are global and rapid Z)  epiphytic plants such as many orchids are considered parasitic plants",
        "Answer": "Z)  EPIPHYTIC PLANTS SUCH AS MANY ORCHIDS ARE CONSIDERED PARASITIC PLANTS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following is MOST likely to be measured as 200 yottameters:  W)  radius of the observable universe X)  Pluto\u00d5s orbital diameter Y)  distance to Andromeda Z)  distance to Ganymede",
        "Answer": "W)  RADIUS OF THE OBSERVABLE UNIVERSE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "ENCE  Multiple Choice  Some vitamin tablets contain high concentrations of zinc and must be formulated to include high levels of which of the following minerals in order to prevent an induced anemia:   W)  copper X)  calcium Y)  magnesium Z)  boron",
        "Answer": "W)  COPPER"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  What is the most common name for the technique that places a molecule in a strong magnetic field, irradiates the molecule with radio waves, and finally detects changes in the spin of atoms in the molecule?",
        "Answer": "NUCLEAR MAGNETIC RESONANCE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following instruments is BEST used to image small, transparent and fluorescent specimens and obtain optical sections without the need for mechanical sectioning:  W)  X-ray microanalyzer X)  scanning electron microscope Y)  transmission electron microscope Z)  confocal laser scanning microscope",
        "Answer": "Z)  CONFOCAL LASER SCANNING MICROSCOPE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  A relatively new scourge to the citrus growers in Florida, what is the common name of the citrus disease caused by a species of bacteria called C. liberibacter and spread by an introduced non-native insect?",
        "Answer": "GREENING"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "ENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following is a mint-flavoring used in chewing gum, toothpaste, and mouthwashes produced naturally in fruits and vegetables:  W)  wintergreen X)  xylitol Y)  winterol Z)  arabinose",
        "Answer": "X)  XYLITOL"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "ENCE  Multiple Choice  The separation of proteins using SDS polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis is primarily based on:  W)  charge only X)  charge and shape Y)  molecular mass Z)  shape only",
        "Answer": "Y)  MOLECULAR MASS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "ENCE  Multiple Choice  A primary consequence of acid rain in the northeast U.S. has been:  W)  salt-water intrusion in coastal wells  X)  the leaching out of toxic heavy metals in lakes and streams Y)  increase in radioactive decay of parent bedrock Z)  increased algal growth to cause eutrophication in lakes",
        "Answer": "X)  THE LEACHING OUT OF"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  About two-thirds of the cause of acid precipitation is the production of sulfuric acid in the atmosphere.  The production of what acid accounts for about the other one-third of acid rain?",
        "Answer": "NITRIC ACID"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following statements is LEAST accurate:  W)  the molecular formula for dimethyl sulfoxide is C2H6SO X)  black smokers are a type of hydrothermal vent found on the ocean floor Y)  Io is the most volcanically active body in our Solar System Z)  on a weather map, an adjacent series of closed half-circles along a line represents a cold front",
        "Answer": "Z)  ON A WEATHER MAP, AN ADJACENT SERIES OF CLOSED HALF-CIRCLES ALONG A LINE REPRESENTS A COLD FRONT"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following is NOT generally true regarding the hydrologic cycle world-wide:  W)  glaciers are shrinking X)  river discharge is decreasing Y)  precipitation at high altitudes is increasing Z)  the thickness of sea ice over the Arctic Ocean is decreasing",
        "Answer": "X)  RIVER DISCHARGE IS DECREASING"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  In Africa it is estimated that about 200 million people are infected with what water-borne parasitic disease known as Bilharzia?",
        "Answer": "SHISTOSOMIASIS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "ENCE  Multiple Choice  A steroid will dissolve BEST in which of the following:  W)  acetone X)  50% ethanol Y)  95% ethanol Z)  distilled water",
        "Answer": "W)  ACETONE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Consider a pond that has high amounts of phosphorus and nitrogen.  The pond shows signs of large amounts of algae.  This pond would most likely be considered:  W)  anticlinic X)  oligotrophic  (read as:  oh-lig-oh-tro-fick) Y)  synclinic Z)  eutrophic",
        "Answer": "Z)  EUTROPHIC"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  The galvanic series typically lists metals in which of the following orders:   W)  cathodic versus anodic X)  passive versus reactive Y)  pure metal versus alloy  Z)  lowest to highest electrode potential",
        "Answer": "W)  CATHODIC VERSUS ANODIC"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  What is the name of the hybrid super computer in Yokohama, Japan, specifically designed for atmospheric modeling calculations?",
        "Answer": "THE EARTH SIMULATOR"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following BEST describes the field of study called spintronics:  W)  studying the angular momentum of celestial bodies X)  using high strength centripetal forces to separate materials in solution Y)  nanoscale electronics that involve manipulation and observation of electron spin Z)  quantum manipulation of quark and gluon spin states",
        "Answer": "Y)  NANOSCALE ELECTRONICS THAT INVOLVE MANIPULATION AND OBSERVATION OF ELECTRON SPIN"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "ENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following is TRUE:  W)  neutrinos released from Fermi National Lab in Illinois have been detected by an underground facility in Minnesota X)  the European Space Agency\u00d5s Planck Surveyor recently confirmed a critical postulate of string theory Y)  baryonic matter accounts for most of the mass of the universe Z)  the LISA detector recently detected gravitational waves from 2 colliding black holes",
        "Answer": "W)  NEUTRINOS RELEASED FROM FERMI NATIONAL LAB IN ILLINOIS HAVE BEEN DETECTED BY AN UNDERGROUND FACILITY IN MINNESOTA"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  Your boat has a true course of 88\u00bc, the variation is 18\u00bc west, and the deviation is 12\u00bc west.  What is your compass course, in degrees?",
        "Answer": "118"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  The famous hominid skeleton called Lucy has been dated to be how many years old:  W)  100 thousand years X)  500 thousand years Y)  1.6 million years Z)  3.2 million years",
        "Answer": "Z)  3.2 MILLION YEARS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following statements is LEAST accurate:  W)  a U.S. barrel of crude oil is 42 gallons X)  one barrel of U.S. crude oil typically yields about 20 gallons of motor gasoline Y)  the distillation step in crude oil refinement typically eliminates nearly all the sulfur Z)  a U.S. barrel of crude oil can yield more than 44 gallons of petroleum products",
        "Answer": "Y)  THE DISTILLATION STEP IN CRUDE OIL REFINEMENT TYPICALLY ELIMINATES NEARLY ALL THE SULFUR"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "ENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following is NOT true:  W)  electron tunneling is a phenomenon known since the early formulations of quantum mechanics X)  interstellar dust is now believed to constitute less than 1% of the mass in the interstellar medium Y)  antibiotic resistance in bacteria can arise from bacteria incorporating exogenous DNA into their genomes Z)  plant auxin is typically produced in bud scales and has the restricted role of cellular elongation",
        "Answer": "Z)  PLANT AUXIN IS TYPICALLY PRODUCED IN BUD SCALES AND HAS THE RESTRICTED ROLE OF CELLULAR ELONGATION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  If the magic sum for a magic square is 15 and the top row of the magic square consists of  the numbers 2, 9 and 4 and the top two numbers of the left column from the top down are 2 and 7, what are the 3 rows, from top to bottom?",
        "Answer": "816357492"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following is NOT typically true about lichens:  W)  lichens produce a rock-dissolving acid as they grow X)  few animals other than caribou can eat lichens Y)  lichens take nutrients from the air  Z)  lichens are prone to desiccation and death if water is withheld for more than a few days",
        "Answer": "Z)  LICHENS ARE PRONE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  What general class of plant hormones and their synthetic cousins have been used as herbicides such as 2,4-D and agent orange?",
        "Answer": "AUXINS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "ENCE  Multiple Choice  An isotonic solution of sodium chloride, also known as normal saline, is what percent by mass:  W)  0.045% X)  0.9% Y)  2.5% Z)  10%",
        "Answer": "X)  0.9%"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "ENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following BEST describes the size of a typical animal virus:  W)  600 micrometers X)  100 nanometers Y)  1 nanometer Z)  1 angstrom",
        "Answer": "X)  100 NANOMETERS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following is a trace element in coal that is a pollutant and neurotoxin released into the atmosphere when coal is burned, for which some states are currently developing technologies to reduce these emissions by 70 to 90%:  W)  sulfur X)  mercury Y)  carbon Z)  chromium",
        "Answer": "X)  MERCURY"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  What is the term for the process of the addition of small amounts of certain elements that makes semiconductors become useful electronic materials?",
        "Answer": "DOPING"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "ENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following is closest to the conversion of 900 millibars into atmospheres:  W)  0.09 X)  0.9 Y)  9.0 Z)  90.0",
        "Answer": "X)  0.9"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  Convert 2,000 meters per second into kilometers per hour:",
        "Answer": "7,200"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Suppose you measured the voltage of a fully-charged 12-volt battery and you get 3 identical results of 10.45 volts.  Which of the following BEST describes your data:  W)  precise but not accurate  X)  accurate but not precise Y)  both accurate and precise Z)  neither accurate nor precise",
        "Answer": "W)  PRECISE BUT NOT ACCURATE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  Giving your answer in proper scientific notation, convert 100 millimeters into kilometers:",
        "Answer": "1 x 10-4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "ENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following numbers has 6 significant figures:  W)  55.0000 X)  555,000 Y)  0.00500 Z)  0.55000",
        "Answer": "W)  55.0000"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  What is the Roman numeral equivalent of the year 1776?",
        "Answer": "MDCCLXXVI"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following is MOST closely related to the mosquito:  W)  fly X)  wasp Y)  human body louse Z)  dragonfly",
        "Answer": "W)  FLY"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following vitamins is NOT properly matched with its function in humans:  W)  vitamin E and antioxidant action  X)  vitamin C and collagen production Y)  vitamin D and calcium absorption  Z)  vitamin A and absorption of iron",
        "Answer": "Z)  VITAMIN A AND ABSORPTION OF IRON"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "ENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following BEST describes the size of the average amoeba:  W)  1 angstrom X)  2 micrometers Y)  600 micrometers Z)  1 centimeter",
        "Answer": "Y)  600 MICROMETERS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  Rounded to the nearest whole number, convert 283K into degrees Fahrenheit:",
        "Answer": "50"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  Which of the following 5 sources accounts for the largest share of energy used in the U.S.:  coal;  petroleum products;  nuclear energy;  renewable energy;  natural gas",
        "Answer": "PETROLEUM PRODUCTS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  In 2004, 19.7 million barrels of petroleum products were used each day in the U.S.  Rounded to the nearest gallon, how much does this represent per person per day?",
        "Answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "ENCE  Multiple Choice  Case hardening is a process through which:  W)  the surface of a metal is hardened X)  the metal is hardened completely through Y)  the hardness of a metal is determined Z)  metals are shaped or formed",
        "Answer": "W)  THE SURFACE OF A METAL IS HARDENED"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "ENCE  Multiple Choice  The oil used with an oil-immersion objective in compound light microscopes takes advantage of what optical phenomenon to improve magnification:  W)  chromatic coherence X)  index of refraction Y)  polarization Z)  dispersion",
        "Answer": "X)  INDEX OF REFRACTION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  One metric ton equals how many grams?",
        "Answer": "ONE MILLION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  Gout in humans is the result of the precipitation of what substance in joints?",
        "Answer": "URIC ACID"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "ENCE  Multiple Choice  As a close relative to the bacteria that cause botulism and gas gangrene, which of the following bacteria are a growing concern in hospitals, killing patients who have been treated with antibiotics:  W)  Bacillus anthracis (read as: an-THRAY-sis) X)  Clostridium difficile Y)  Treponema pallidium  (read as: Trep-oh-KNEE-mah pal-LID-ee-um) Z)  Vibrio cholera",
        "Answer": "X)  CLOSTRIDIUM DIFFICILE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "ENCE  Multiple Choice  The length of the longest side of a U.S. dollar bill is about how many nanometers in length:  W)  70 million  X)  1.10 ! 106  Y)  1.55 ! 108  Z)  600 million",
        "Answer": "Y)  1.55 ! 108"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  In a recent breakthrough announcement by the CDC, which of the following diseases has been shown to have both a genetic and physiological component:   W)  malaria X)  chronic fatigue syndrome Y)  Tay Sach\u00d5s disease Z)  sleeping sickness",
        "Answer": "X)  CHRONIC FATIGUE SYNDROME"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  Name all of the following 4 diseases that are NOT caused by bacteria:  cholera;  bubonic plague;  syphilis;  mumps",
        "Answer": "MUMPS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "ENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following is the BEST description of an ecological niche:  W)  a situation in which a species is well adapted to a specific set of environmental conditions X)  the biomass load of a given environment Y)  a pollutant that becomes concentrated in organisms as it moves up through the food chain Z)  all the environmental conditions, plants, and animals of an isolated area",
        "Answer": "W)  A SITUATION IN WHICH A SPECIES IS WELL ADAPTED"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  Lichens are a symbiotic relationship of what 2 general types of organisms?",
        "Answer": "GREEN ALGAE AND FUNGI"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  To remove this parasite that erupts from the skin, victims will wrap the end of the emerging worm around a stick and turn the stick over a period of days to slowly remove the worm:  W)  Ascaris X)  guinea worm Y)  hookworm Z)  strongyloid",
        "Answer": "X)  GUINEA WORM"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  Name all of the following that are primarily bacterial diseases:  diphtheria;  herpes zoster;  strep throat;  rubella;  yellow fever",
        "Answer": "DIPHTHERIA;  STREP THROAT"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer   What neurotransmitter is deficient in Parkinson\u00d5s disease?",
        "Answer": "DOPAMINE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "ENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following is the BEST reason why Parkinson\u00d5s disease cannot be treated by simply administering dopamine into the blood stream:  W)  dopamine\u00d5s blood half-life is too short X)  dopamine will not cross the blood brain barrier Y)  dopamine is the precursor to the real effective transmitter in Parkinson\u00d5s disease Z)  it is not known why dopamine will not work if administered directly into the blood",
        "Answer": "X)  DOPAMINE WILL NOT CROSS THE BLOOD BRAIN BARRIER"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following is MOST commonly used for removing many organic compounds in water in municipal water treatment plants:  W)  activated charcoal X)  precipitation reactions Y)  reverse osmosis Z)  dredging",
        "Answer": "W)  ACTIVATED CHARCOAL"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following is NOT true:  W)  the epilimnion is the upper warm layer of water of a lake in summer X)  in cameras, the larger the f-number, the greater the depth of field Y)  crab grass is better adapted to hot dry weather than Kentucky blue grass Z)  Listeria is a waterborne parasite",
        "Answer": "Z)  LISTERIA IS A WATERBORNE PARASITE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "ENCE  Multiple Choice  Ed the entomologist is setting up mosquito traps in a farmer\u2122s field in Nebraska.  Which of the following would be the BEST mosquito attractant to ensure he traps the greatest number and variety of mosquitoes:  W)  oxygen  X)  nitrogen  Y)  dry ice Z)  methane",
        "Answer": "Y)  DRY ICE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  Rounded to the nearest whole number, convert 3,000 meters per second into kilometers per hour:",
        "Answer": "10,800"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  A standard rain gauge consists of a metal canister open at the top in which a funnel drains rainwater into a narrow cylinder.  Each time they are deployed to the field, a small amount of light oil is added to the cylinder.  This is done to:  W)  deter birds from drinking the water X)  stop the canister from oxidizing Y)  prevent the growth of blue-green algae Z)  prevent water evaporation",
        "Answer": "Z)  PREVENT WATER EVAPORATION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following is a widely-used analgesic and antipyretic medication which is not considered an NSAID (read as: en-say\u2122d):  W)  acetylcysteine X)  acetaminophen Y)  acetylsalicylic acid Z)  ibuprophen",
        "Answer": "X)  ACETAMINOPHEN"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "ENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following best illustrates a limitation of a supercapacitor, or electric double-layer capacitor, versus an electrochemical battery:  W)  virtually unlimited cycle life X)  rapid recharging Y)  low impedance Z)  high self-discharge rate",
        "Answer": "Z)  HIGH SELF-DISCHARGE RATE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  If it is 7:47 AM, Tuesday September 23rd  in  Beijing China at 116\u00ba east longitude, what day and time, respectively, would it be in London, England?",
        "Answer": "TUESDAY;  12:47 AM"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following age groups would have the most brown fat per kilogram of body weight:  W)  infant X)  adolescent Y)  middle age Z)  elderly",
        "Answer": "W)  INFANT"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following physiological processes generates most of the heat needed to keep an infant warm:  W)  digestion of food in the gut X)  oxidative metabolism Y)  inspiration of air Z)  bacterial activity in the gut",
        "Answer": "X)  OXIDATIVE METABOLISM"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  1 bar equals how many Pascals?",
        "Answer": "100,000"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  Meteorologists commonly use the hectopascal for air pressure.  1,000 hectopascals equals how many millibars?",
        "Answer": "1,000"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Bioluminescence is a phenomenon most common in which of the following environments:  W)  marine X)  fresh water Y)  land Z)  atmosphere",
        "Answer": "W)  MARINE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following is a mixing incompatibility of common household products that can produce toxic products:  W)  vinegar and baking soda X)  vinegar and bleach  Y)  vinegar and borax  Z)  castile soap and salt",
        "Answer": "X)  VINEGAR AND BLEACH"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  Giving your answer to the first decimal place, an increase  of 1\u00baC is equivalent to an increase of how many degrees Fahrenheit?",
        "Answer": "1.8"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  Convert 140\u00baF into degrees Celsius:",
        "Answer": "60"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following is NOT true:  W)  only a few harmful algal bloom species actually produce toxins that are poisonous to people X)  algal blooms occur in marine and freshwater environments Y)  algal blooms can occur in the open ocean far from any coastal inlets Z)  pollution is always to blame for harmful algal blooms along coastal waters",
        "Answer": "Z)  POLLUTION IS ALWAYS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  500 metric gigatons is approximately equal to how many pounds:  W)  1.1 trillion X)  11 trillion Y)  110 trillion Z)  1,100 trillion",
        "Answer": "Z)  1,100 TRILLION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Pyrex glass contains many of the same components as soda lime glass but in addition contains at least 5%:  W)  boric acid X)  pure silica Y)  clay Z)  dyes",
        "Answer": "W)"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following BEST describes the function of boric acid in the manufacture of Pyrex or borosilicate glass:  W)  makes the glass more scratch-resistant  X)  makes the glass more brittle Y)  reduces the linear coefficient of expansion of the glass Z)  reduces the effect of detrimental ultraviolet light exposure",
        "Answer": "Y)  REDUCES THE LINEAR COEFFICIENT OF EXPANSION OF THE GLASS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  Pitchblende is one of the main ores of what element?",
        "Answer": "URANIUM"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  Order the following 3 temperature values from the COOLEST to the WARMEST:  32\u00baC;  85\u00baF;  310 K",
        "Answer": "85\u00baF;  32\u00baC;  310 K"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  The largest deposits of diatomite, or diatomaceous earth, are typically found in which of the following regions of the U.S.:  W)  western X)  eastern Y)  midwest Z)  southern",
        "Answer": "W)  WESTERN"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Diatomite, or diatomaceous earth, is readily available in the U.S. and is used primarily for which of the following functions:  W)  soil improvement X)  crushed stone Y)  filtering agent  Z)  lubricant",
        "Answer": "Y)  FILTERING AGENT"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  Name 2 of the following 4 choices that are the 2 main logical reasoning methods used in science:  inductive;  synthetic;  observational;  deductive",
        "Answer": "INDUCTIVE;  DEDUCTIVE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  To the nearest whole number, convert 50\u00baF into kelvin:",
        "Answer": "283"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Multiple",
        "Question": "IENCE  Multiple Choice  Which of the following is a jaw-less fish:  W)  lungfish X)  catfish Y)  lamprey Z)  sturgeon",
        "Answer": "Y)  LAMPREY"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "GENERAL",
        "Type": "SCIENCE Short",
        "Question": "SCIENCE  Short Answer  In the northern hemisphere, name all of the following 4 northern degree latitudes that will experience a 12-hour length of day during the vernal equinox:   0\u00ba;  10\u00ba;  15\u00ba;  20\u00ba",
        "Answer": "ALL"
    }
]